Guide to the Daniel Bell Research Files on U.S. Communism, Socialism, and the Labor Movement TAM.080
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VII: Addendum
  - Subseries VII:A: Writings; Research Correspondence & Materials.
    - Communist Party Platform, 1921 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (David Riesman, et al), 1952-1957 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re Tamiment Institute Purchase of Fund for the Republic Collection, 1959 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Denitch, Faith: Correspondence, 1958 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Goldsmith, William: Clippings, 1950s (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Goldsmith, William: Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Jewish War Veterans, undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Subseries VII:B: Writings; Research Correspondence & Materials.
    - Aaron, D. Men of Good Hope. Review by Daniel Bell., undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - American Federation of Labor. (publications), 1941-1956 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Bell, Daniel. Chapter V. "Fission, Fusion, and Faction.", undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Bell, Daniel. Chapter VI. "The Golden Age." (1/2), undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Bell, Daniel. Chapter VI. "The Golden Age." (2/2), undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Bell, Daniel. Chapter XI. "Playboys.", undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Bell, Daniel. Chapter XII. "In Dubious Battle.", undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Bell, Daniel. Chapter XIII. "The Days of Sere and Yellow Leaf. ", undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Bell, Daniel. Marx Lenin Chapter Notes., undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Bell, Daniel. "Labor's New Men of Power.", 1953 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Bell, Daniel. "Language of Labor.", undated (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Bell, Daniel. "The New Economy.", 1955 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Bell, Daniel. Working Notes and Materials. (found as a unit), undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Bell, Daniel. Working Notes and Materials. (found as a unit), undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Bell, Daniel. Working Notes and Materials. (found as a unit), undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Bell, Daniel. Working Notes and Materials. (found as a unit), undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Bell, Daniel. Working Notes, miscellaneous., undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Bell, Daniel. Working Notes on Unions., undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Brophy, John (CIO): Interview by William Goldsmith, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Browder, Earl. Interviews by D. Bell and W. Goldsmith (1/2), Jun 1955-Aug 1955 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Browder, Earl. Interviews by D. Bell and W. Goldsmith (2/2), Jun 1955-Aug 1955 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Browder, Earl. Marx and America (galley proofs), 1958 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Browder, Earl. "Relations Between the Communist Party of America and the Communist International.", ca.1956 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Browder, Earl. Review of P. Selznick, The Organization Weapon, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Bundenz, Louis F. Men Without Faces(excerpts), 1948 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Carey, Jim. Interview (27 October 1955) (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Chaplin, Ralph. Wobbly. Review by Daniel Bell., 1948 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (printed material), 1937 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (printed material), 1938 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (printed material), 1946-1948 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations: Public Workers Expulsion. (typescript), 1950 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations: Rubber Workers. (notes and interview), undated (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Communism, New Party Line, U.S. Labor. (clippings), 1953 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America. House Un American Activities Committee Report., 1938 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America (publications and notes), 1938 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America (publications and notes), 1939 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America (publications and notes), 1940 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Communist Parties, U.S.A., General, Labor. (publications), 1948-1955 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Communist Parties, Western Europe, Strategy, Labor movements. (publications), 1939-1953 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence to and from Daniel Bell., 1951-1959 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Debs, Eugene Victor (clippings and notes), undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - De Leon, Daniel. (typescript) (1/2), undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - De Leon, Daniel. (typescript) (2/2), undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Economics, Collective Bargaining, Wage Theory, Impact of Unions. (typescripts) (1/2), 1947-1954 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Economics, Collective Bargaining, Wage Theory, Impact of Unions. (typescripts) (2/2), 1947-1954 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Fleischer, Henry (C.I.O.). Interview., Oct 20, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Fey, John (AFL). Interview by William Goldsmith., Nov 10, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Goldin, Clint. Interview., Oct 26, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - The Autobiography of William D. Haywood: Review by Daniel Bell., undated (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Hillman, Sidney. (typescript), undated (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Hillquit, Morris. (clippings and notes), 1932-1934 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Hoan, Daniel W. (Mayor of Milwaukee). (clippings and notes), 1933-1936 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Kornfeder, Joseph Zack. (notes), undated (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Leites, N.C. "The Third International and its Changes of Policy...", 1942 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Meany, George (typescript), 1953-1955 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Merrill, Lewis Cawan (notes), undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Mobilization, Politicking, Wilson, Labor (article and notes), undated (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - National Maritime Union of America. (publication), undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Needle Trades (publications), 1927-1953 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Needle Trade Workers Industrial Union. (publications), 1928-1929 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Non Partisan League of North Dakota. (notes), 1947 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Norris, George W. (Nebraska Senator). (speeches), 1925-1933 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Passaic, New Jersey Strike, Trade Union Line. (typescript), 1925 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Political Sociology, Radicalism, Theory of Factionalism. (article and notes), undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Pressman, Leo (CIO). Interviews., 1955-1956 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Productivity. (publications), 1940-1959 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Publications, miscellaneous., 1944-1960 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Radical Sects, U.S.A., (clippings and notes), 1930s (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Saposs, David. Interview., Oct 20, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. "What About Communism?", 1949 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Scottsboro: Non Partisan Labor Defense League Pamphlet., undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Social Movements, Radicalism, Trotskyism, Cannon - We Have Split. (1/2) (publications), 1953-1954 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Social Movements, Radicalism, Trotskyism, Cannon - We Have Split. (2/2) (clippings), 1953-1954 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Socialist Party election results (notes), 1900, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Socialist Party U.S.A., (publications and notes), 1950s (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Syndicalism, France, England, Relations with Communist Party. (notes), undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Thomas, Norman (typescripts), undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Trade Union Education League (minutes), 1927 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Union Attitudes: Productivity, Technological Change (publications), 1953-1962 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Unions, miscellaneous (publications), 1943-1956 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Unions: Race Relations, Union Policy (publications), 1953 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Unions: White Collar, Engineering Unions, Labor (publications), 1949-1954 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - United Furniture Workers of America (proceedings), 1939-1954 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - United Office and Professional Workers of America Pproceedingsand clippings), 1938-1947 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - United Steel Workers (Dave McDonald). (typescript), 1956 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - United States Government Labor Force, Trends in Public Employment. (publications), 1953 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Widick, B.J. Memo on the Communist Party. (typescript), 1958 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Zimmerman, Charles. Files item list., undated (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Almond Interviews. Transcript., undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. [3 Discs transferred to Sound Archives], 1921-1924 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Discs - Browder Interviews. [Discs transferred to Sound Archives], undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Discs [Discs transferred to Sound Archives] & Miscellaneous notes {re Browder, etc.}, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - [Discs transferred to Sound Archives], undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - [Discs transferred to Sound Archives], undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Duplicates, 1940s-1950s (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Duplicates, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Originals of photocopied materials, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)